(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
ござる☆ござれ
Gozaru☆Gozare
なんでもござれと
Come what may!
切り捨てごめんのマジカル☆ワールド
A "Cut-and-Pardon" Magical☆World
魔法少女ましまる☆ござる
Magical Girl Mashimaru Gozaru
魔法の呪文
A magic spell
マジカル☆ござるへ Let's Go!!
To Magical☆Gozaru, Let's Go!!
朝日が目覚めたら遅刻寸前
Waking up to the morning sun, I'm almost late
お気に入りの草鞋を履いたなら
Once I put on my favorite straw sandals
駆け抜ける畦道
I'll run through the paths between the fields
駆け抜ける迷道
Running through the labyrinth
A to the G
Not ジャキンジャキン
Not clank-clank
Yes マジカルワンド
Yes, magical wand
どこから見ても魔法少女なり
A magical girl, no matter where you look
ひれ伏せものども
Bowing down, everyone
私腹を肥やす　悪代官らたち
To the corrupt officials lining their pockets
ちょうどよいわい　大分可愛い
Just right, and quite cute
拙者のワンドの錆になるでござる!!
You shall become rust on my wand, de-gozaru!!
マジカルワンド斬り!!!!!
Magical Wand Slash!!!!!
GOZARU☆GOZARE　討ち入りでござる
GOZARU GOZARE, it's a raid, de-gozaru
マジカルなみねうちを　お見舞いするでござる
I'll treat you to a magical back-blade strike, de-gozaru
GOZARU☆GOZARE　この世界を守る
GOZARU GOZARE, I will protect this world
完璧に可憐な姿　ご覧あれ
Behold my perfectly lovely form
魔法少女まじかる☆ござる
Magical Girl Magical Gozaru
フリフリヒラヒラ　そよ風に舞う袴の裾を
Fluttering and waving, the hem of my hakama dancing in the breeze
ちょんとつまんで決めポーズ　崇めよものども
Pinching it slightly for a finishing pose, worship me, everyone
ござるランドの　麗しきお姫様
The beautiful princess of Gozaru Land
だけど言えない　その正体
But I can't reveal my true identity
秘密こそ至上のテンプレでござる
Secrets are the ultimate trope, de-gozaru
GOZARU☆GOZARE　闇討ちでござる
GOZARU GOZARE, it's a night attack, de-gozaru
魔法少女は食わねど　高楊枝でござる
A magical girl goes hungry but keeps a toothpick high, de-gozaru
GOZARU☆GOZARE　魔法の国から
GOZARU GOZARE, from the land of magic
お忍びで舞い降りた　謎の転校生
The mysterious transfer student who descended in secret
魔法少女まじかる☆ござる
Magical Girl Magical Gozaru
そんな風に素敵を作りたい
I want to create wonders like that
いつだって可愛くなりたいと願う
Always wishing to become cute
忘れちゃいけない魔法　守りたいでござる
I want to protect the magic I must never forget, de-gozaru
GOZARU☆GOZARE　いつまでもござる
GOZARU GOZARE, always de-gozaru
胸キュンな一撃を　お見舞いするでござる
I'll treat you to a heart-throbbing blow, de-gozaru
GOZARU☆GOZARE　この世界を守る
GOZARU GOZARE, I will protect this world
完璧に可憐な姿　ご覧あれ
Behold my perfectly lovely form
魔法少女まじかる☆ござる
Magical Girl Magical Gozaru
M-P!!
魔法の呪文
Magic spell
M-P!!
まじかる☆ござる
Magical Gozaru
Let's Go!!
Chu chu yeah!
Please me!
Without you!
あー！ なんてことだ 些細な過ちだ
Ah! Good grief, what a trivial mistake
自分のことに タラッタラッタ 手焼く
Handling my own business is such a hassle
どうして突然？ 逃げ切ったっていいでしょ？
Why so sudden? It's okay to run away, right?
だけどなんだか 気まぐれモードになり
But somehow I've gone into whimsical mode
そんな気分になっちゃって
I've just ended up in that kind of mood
始まりはそんな風で
That's how it all started
つまりはらしくないようで
In other words, it seems unlike me
でも今じゃ 扉開けてほら 声が聞こえるよ さあ 行こう！
But now, look, open the door, I can hear a voice, come on, let's go!
僕は君の翼に なれる勇気があるよ！
I have the courage to become your wings!
(Please stay with me)
どんな試練も怖くない その魔法があるから
I'm not afraid of any trial because I have that magic
初めて出会う世界に 花束を贈ろう
Let's send a bouquet to the world we meet for the first time
ただこの瞬間 結ばれるよ
Just at this moment, we'll be connected
ちぐはぐなコミュニケーション でも別に構わない
Awkward communication, but it doesn't really matter
明日から平和なら！
If there's peace from tomorrow onwards!
Chu chu yeah!
Without you!
ああ どうしてまた 素直になれなくて
Ah, why can't I be honest again?
自分のことで チュルルチュルッチュ 手焼く
Handling my own business is such a hassle
ギアはそのまま スピード上げていこう
Keep the gear as it is, let's speed up
だけどなんだか 黄昏モードになり
But somehow I've gone into twilight mode
いつかを思い出しちゃって 一人でいても嫌じゃない
Remembering some time, it's not bad to be alone
誰にも頼らなくてもいい
It's okay if you don't rely on anyone
でも扉の向こう　騒がしい
But beyond the door, it's noisy
声が聞きたいよ　今！
I want to hear your voice, now!
行こう！
Let's go!
僕は君を背中に
I'll take you on my back
乗せて空を舞うよ！
And we'll fly through the sky!
please fly with me
いつか心が離れても
Even if our hearts drift apart someday
その時は笑ってて
Please keep smiling then
守りたいこの世界に
In this world I want to protect
青空のラプソディ
A blue sky rhapsody
make me rhapsodic!
ただいつまでも奏でていてよ
Just keep playing it forever
デコボコなコンビネーションでも別に大丈夫だ
Even if we're an awkward combination, it's okay
明日はまだ平和だ
Tomorrow will still be peaceful
ほんの小さな傷を
Expose those tiny little wounds
太陽にさらして
To the sun
分け合ったよ君と
I shared them with you
痛みは熱さの中に溶けてく！
The pain melts away into the heat!
chu chu yeah!
エセトラなビート弾く僕ら
We're playing an "et cetera" beat
手を叩いて
Clap your hands
chu chu yeah!
ブギーなリズムではしゃぐ二人
Two people having fun with a boogie rhythm
飛び跳ねてさ
Jump around
chu chu yeah!
エセトラなビート弾く僕ら
We're playing an "et cetera" beat
手を叩いて
Clap your hands
chu chu yeah!
ブギーなリズムではしゃぐアリーナ！
Everyone in the arena, have fun with a boogie rhythm!
ヘイ！ヘイ！ヘイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey!
僕は君の翼に　なれる勇気があるよ！
I have the courage to become your wings!
please stay with me
どんな試練も怖くない
I'm not afraid of any trial
その魔法があるから
Because I have that magic
君と出会い世界は　花束に溢れた
Meeting you filled the world with bouquets
made in society
ただこの瞬間　結ばれたよ
We're united in this very moment
チグハグなコミュニケーションでも別に構わない
I don't mind if our communication is awkward
明日が平和なら！
As long as tomorrow is peaceful!
chu chu yeah!
please me!
息を切らし
Out of breath
without you!
というわけで、皆様！こんばんはでござる〜！
And with that, everyone! Good evening!
風真いろは生誕ライブ2024にお越しくださいまして、
Thank you so much for coming to the
本当にありがとうございます！見てる〜？
Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2024! Are you watching?
はい、というわけで、皆様もうすでにお気づきかと思いますが、
Alright, I think everyone has noticed by now,
本日のハッシュタグはこちらでございます。見てますか？
But here is today's hashtag. Can you see it?
はい、#風真いろは生誕ライブ2024 で今日はたくさんXにスクショも、感想も、
Please post lots of screenshots, impressions,
思ったこと全部、おたけびまで、全部ポストしてください！
Everything you're thinking, and even your shouts on X
誕生日おめでとうコメント見てるよ！みんなありがとう！
I'm seeing all the "Happy Birthday" comments! Thank you everyone!
はい、というわけでここまで2曲続けてお送りさせていただきましたが、
Alright, so I've performed two songs in a row now,
予告通り1曲目は『魔法少女マジカルござる』を披露させていただきました！どうだったかな？
As promised, the first song was "Magical Girl Magical Gozaru"! How was it?
実は今回、MVを作っていただいたクリエイターさんにもですね、事前にお伝えはしていたものの、
Actually, I told the creators who made the MV beforehand,
なんと振り付け結構MV準拠でやらせていただきました！
But I actually performed the choreography mostly based on the MV!
はい、ということで！そうなんです！今回のライブテーマは『なりたい自分』ということで、
Yes! That's right! Today's live theme is "The person I want to be"...
1つ目、まず魔法少女でお送りさせていただきました！ステージはこんな感じです！どうぞ〜！
...so first, I performed as a Magical Girl! This is what the stage looks like! Take a look!
すっげー！なんかめっちゃピンクだし、
Wow! It's so pink,
めっちゃ星とか月とかあって素敵でしょう、これ！
And there are so many stars and moons, isn't it wonderful?
めちゃめちゃいいでしょう！はい、やっぱり強くて可愛くてカッコいい魔法少女っていうのはね、
It's so good, right! Well, a strong, cute, and cool Magical Girl...
私の憧れだったんで、今回ライブでやりたいなと思ってやらせていただきました。
...has always been something I've admired, so I wanted to do it for this live.
あ、そうそう、あとこのライブとは別枠で、えっと今ね、
Oh, that's right. Aside from this live,
魔法少女プロジェクトが公式さんから、えっと発信されておりますが、
The official "Magical Girl Project" is currently underway,
あの、別物でござるがね、ぜひそちらも、あのチェックしてくだされでござる！
But it's a separate thing! Please be sure to check that out as well!
はい、そしてですね、2曲目は『青空のラプソディ』やらせていただきました。
And then, for the second song, I performed "Blue Sky Rhapsody".
こちらもね、魔法繋がりでしたね。皆様お気づきになりましたか？
That one also had a magic theme. Did you all notice?
お、そういえばすっかり忘れていたんですけど、皆様、
Oh, wait, I completely forgot, but everyone...
何か見慣れないものがありましたね。
...there was something you're not used to seeing, wasn't there?
やっぱ出そうかなって思うんですけど、出していいですか？
I think I should bring it out. Is it okay?
では、いいですか？
Well then, are you ready?
行きますよ！
Here I go!
せーの！
One, two...!
出でよ！
Come forth!
マジカルワンド...
Magical Wand...
出てるー！
It's out!
ちょっとごめん、皆。風真いろはの魔法の力強すぎて、
Sorry everyone. Kazama Iroha's magic power was too strong,
風真が言い切る前に出たわ。
it came out before I could finish saying it.
ちょっ、ごめんね、強すぎちゃって。
Sorry, it was just too strong.
「俺何かやっちゃいました」状態なんですけれども、
I'm in an "Oh, did I do something again?" state,
マジカルワンドでーす！
but here is the Magical Wand!
はい、いいでしょう、MVと同じやつです、イェイ！
Yes, it's nice, right? It's the same one from the MV, yay!
ということは、皆殿、あれが出来ますね？
That means, everyone, we can do *that*, right?
何回も何回も練習した、
I'd like you all to do that thing
あれを皆殿にやっていただきたいと思うんですけど、
we practiced over and over again.
皆殿、よろしいですかー？
Everyone, are you ready?
はーい！
Yes!
え、スタッフの皆さんもよろしいですかー？
And staff members, are you ready too?
はーいという声が今、風真いろはの耳元に聞こえております。
I can hear the voices of "Yes!" in my ears right now.
それでは、皆、行きますよ。
Alright then, everyone, here we go.
くらえ、マジカルワンド斬り！
Take this, Magical Wand Slash!
はい、今、スタッフさんの声も、
Yes, the staff's voices and
皆殿のコメントも届いてます、ありがとうございます！
everyone's comments are reaching me, thank you very much!
はい、というわけで、このままですね、
Yes, so the Magical Girl part continues,
魔法少女パート続いていくんですけれども、次はゲストパートとなります。
but next up is the guest part.
今回ですね、風真結構勇気を出して
This time, I plucked up quite a bit of courage
いろんなホロメンたちを誘わせていただきましたので、
and invited various Hololive members,
この後もぜひお楽しみ。
so please look forward to it.
次も、えーっと、何だっけ？あ、
Next up is also... what was it? Ah,
魔法少女パートでお送りさせていただきます。
we'll be presenting the Magical Girl part.
はい、それでは次のパートに行ってみましょう。
Alright then, let's head to the next part.
というわけで、次はゲストパート、レッツゴーでござる！
So next is the guest part, let's go!
ブンブンブンブーン！
Vroom vroom vroom vroom!
MOON PRIDE
あなたの力になりたい
I want to be your strength
MOON PRIDE
作詞・作曲 Revo
Lyrics & Composition: Revo
涙は頬を伝い
Tears stream down my cheeks
瞳は赤く燃える
My eyes burn bright red
稲妻のように激しく
Fierce like a bolt of lightning
誰かが愛を叫ぶ
Someone cries out for love
例えどんな
No matter how deep
（暗闇も）
(the darkness)
一人じゃないよね
You're not alone
（私たちを）
(we are)
照らす MOON PRIDE
illuminated by MOON PRIDE
ああ 女の子にも
Ah, even for a girl
譲れない矜持がある
there is a pride that cannot be surrendered
それは王子様に運命投げ出す
Instead of leaving fate to a prince
自ら戦う意志
it's the will to fight for ourselves
Shiny Make-up 輝くよ
Shiny Make-up, I'll shine
星空を集めて
gathering the starlight
ただ守られるだけの
I'm not some fragile being
儚い存在じゃないわ
who just needs protecting
悲しみの波に揺られ
Swayed by waves of sadness
怒りの火に焼かれても
even if scorched by fires of anger
稲妻のように眩く
Dazzling like a bolt of lightning
永遠の愛を誓う
I vow eternal love
例え今
Even if we are
（離れても）
(apart right now)
一人じゃないよね
You're not alone
（私たちを）
(we are)
繋ぐ MOON PRIDE
linked by MOON PRIDE
ああ 女の子には
Ah, for a girl
無敵の武器がある
there is an invincible weapon
それは弱さに寄り添うまなざしと
It's a gaze that embraces weakness
全て受け入れる強さ
and the strength to accept everything
Shiny Make-up 煌めくよ
Shiny Make-up, I'll sparkle
星空に抱かれて
held in the starry sky's embrace
時を超えた絆が
A bond that transcends time
私に勇気をくれる
gives me courage
恋しくて（切なくて）
I miss you (it's painful)
泣きたくなるよ
it makes me want to cry
会いたくて（寂しくて）
I want to see you (I'm lonely)
駆け出しそうなハート
my heart's about to race away
この広い宇宙で
In this vast universe
何度生まれ変わっても
no matter how many times I'm reborn
あなたに恋をする
I will fall in love with you
Shiny Make-up はばたくよ
Shiny Make-up, I'll take flight
星空の彼方へ
beyond the starry sky
罪が廻る世界でも
Even in a world where sin revolves
未来を信じられる
I can believe in the future
だから Shiny Make-up 戦うよ
So Shiny Make-up, I'll fight
星空を纏って
clothed in the starlight
新しい伝説が
A new legend
今ここから始まる
begins right here and now
La La Pretty Guardian Sailor Moon
だだだだ　うお　だいじょばない
Da-da-da-da, whoa, I'm not okay.
ちょっと　蛹になって出直すわ
Wait, I'll turn back into a pupa and try again.
シンデレラ
作詞・作曲：DECO*27
Cinderella
Lyrics/Composition: DECO*27
愛とか恋とか全部くだらない
Love and romance are all worthless.
がっかりするだけ　ダメを知るだけ
It just leads to disappointment and knowing failure.
あたし馬鹿ね　ダサい逆走じゃん
I'm such a fool, going backwards like a loser.
ホントのところは　あなたにモテたい
To tell the truth, I want you to like me.
失敗するのにビビってるだけ
I'm just scared of failing.
加工なしの厳しめの条件じゃ
With these harsh, unfiltered conditions...
ちょっとこんな時どんな顔すればいいか
I'm not sure what kind of face to make right now.
教えてほしい　うぉお
Please tell me, whoa.
ちょっと「愛してる」だとかそんな言葉で
I want to be broken by words...
壊れてみたい
...like "I love you."
じれったいな　ハロー残念なあたし
It's so frustrating. Hello, pathetic me.
うっぱ　困っちゃって　いやいや
Whoops, I'm in trouble. No, no.
じれったいな　決まんないの前髪が
It's so frustrating. My bangs won't stay in place.
うっぱ　怒っちゃって　イライラ
Whoops, now I'm angry and irritated.
だだだだ　うお　大好きは
Da-da-da-da, whoa, my feelings of love...
もっと可愛くなって言いたいのに
...I want to tell you once I'm cuter.
ああ　だだだだ　うお　だいじょばない
Ah, da-da-da-da, whoa, I'm not okay.
ちょっと　蛹になって出直すわ　やぁ
Wait, I'll turn back into a pupa and try again. Yeah.
あ…えと、いや、なんでもない
Ah... um, no, it's nothing.
言いたいこと言えたことないや
I've never been able to say what I want to say.
目と目　止められないの
When our eyes meet, I can't stop it.
逸らしちゃって　まーた自己嫌悪
I look away and fall into self-hatred again.
じれったいな　ハロー残念なあたし
It's so frustrating. Hello, pathetic me.
うっぱ　困っちゃって　いやいや
Whoops, I'm in trouble. No, no.
じれったいな　入んないのこの靴が
It's so frustrating. These shoes won't fit.
うっぱ　怒っちゃって　イライラ
Whoops, now I'm angry and irritated.
鐘が鳴って　灰になって
The bell rings, and I turn to ash.
あたしまだ帰りたくないや
I don't want to go home yet.
バッテンコースへ飛び込んでみたいから
Because I want to dive into the forbidden course.
じれったいな　ハロー残念なあたし
It's so frustrating. Hello, pathetic me.
うっぱ　困っちゃって　いやいや
Whoops, I'm in trouble. No, no.
じれったいな　決まんないの前髪が
It's so frustrating. My bangs won't stay in place.
怒っちゃってる
I'm getting angry.
じれったいな　夜更け前のシンデレラ
It's so frustrating. Cinderella before the late night.
うっぱ　ビビっちゃって　フラフラ
Whoops, I'm scared and dizzy.
じれったいな　ハローをくれたあなたと
It's so frustrating. With you, who gave me a hello...
踊っちゃって　フラフラ
...I'm dancing and feeling dizzy.
だだだだ　うお　大好きは
Da-da-da-da, whoa, my feelings of love...
もっと可愛くなって言いたいのに
...I want to tell you once I'm cuter.
ああ　だだだだ　うお　だいじょばない
Ah, da-da-da-da, whoa, I'm not okay.
ちょっとお待ちになって王子様
Wait a moment, Prince.
だだ　ダメよ順序とか
Da-da, the order is all wrong.
もっと仲良くなってそうじゃないの？
Shouldn't we get closer first?
ああ　だだだだ　ましてだいじょばない
Ah, da-da-da-da, I'm even less okay now.
やっぱ蛹になって出直すわ
I'll definitely turn back into a pupa and try again.
白い雪のプリンセスは
作詞・作曲：のぼる↑
The Snow White Princess is
Lyrics/Composition: Noboru↑
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, mirror.
世界で一番可愛がるのはやめて
Stop being the most affectionate in the world.
棘のような視線迫る
A thorny gaze approaches.
優しいフリした彼女が
She, who pretended to be kind...
素敵な晩餐もてなした
...served a wonderful dinner.
そっと口に含むと　笑み　薄れゆく
When I softly put it in my mouth, the smile fades away.
あぁ　意思の中で夢を見てる
Ah, I'm dreaming within my own will.
いつかのおとぎ話　時が止まる
In a fairytale from sometime, time stops.
お願いKISSで目を醒まして欲しいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss.
白い棺から連れ出すように
As if to take me out of the white coffin.
突き刺さる憎しみはドラマ的な事情
The piercing hatred is a dramatic circumstance.
祈っても王子様はまだ来ない
Even if I pray, the prince still hasn't come.
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, mirror.
ネクタイ任せや頬に挨拶するから
Because I'll leave my tie to you and greet your cheek.
妬みをかわれてしまった
I've become the object of envy.
七人の小人はいるけど
The seven dwarves are here, but...
助ける素振り知らん振りね
...they make no move to help, feigning ignorance.
そっと首を掴まれ
Softly grabbed by the neck...
笑み そっと首を掴まれ
A smile, gently grabbed by the neck
一粒の
A single
涙さえも
tear even
拭えなくて
cannot be wiped away
呼吸もままならない
and I can barely breathe.
視界伏せた
Eyes cast down.
消えそうだから 早く駆けて欲しいの
I'm about to fade away, so I want you to run to me.
訳は聞かないで
Don't ask why.
答えられない
I can't answer.
望まない憎まれは 深い愛の二乗
Unwanted hatred is the square of deep love.
もうすぐでいなくなるのかな
I wonder if I'll be gone soon.
途切れてく
Fading away...
命の音
...is the sound of life.
毒リンゴを食した少女のように
Like the girl who ate the poisoned apple,
眠りにつく
I fall into a slumber.
お願いKISSで 目を覚まして欲しいの
Please wake me up with a KISS.
胸の中の声
The voice inside my chest,
届きますか
does it reach you?
階段を上ったらドアを開けるだけで
If you climb the stairs and just open the door,
見つかるよ
you'll find me.
Ah...
お願いKISSで 目を覚まして欲しいの
Please wake me up with a KISS.
白い棺から連れ出すように
As if leading me out of the white coffin.
突き刺さる憎しみは ドラマティックの事情
The piercing hatred is a dramatic circumstance.
祈っても 君は戻ってこない
Even if I pray, you won't come back.
消えてしまう
I will fade away...
その前に...
...before that happens...
はい、というわけで、
Yes, and so,
コラボパートから3曲をお届けしてまいりました！
we've brought you three songs from the collaboration part!
ソロパートに帰ってきました！ありがとうございます！
I've returned to the solo part! Thank you very much!
はい、というわけでたくさんの先輩方に出演いただきまして、
Yes, and so, with many seniors appearing,
先輩たちと一緒に魔法少女パート、最後もコラボで『ムーン・プライド』を
the magical girl part with the seniors, and the last collab was 'Moon Pride'
やらさせていただきました！
performed!
もうカッコいい、やっぱ美少女戦士ですからね、
So cool, after all, they're Pretty Guardians, right?
やっぱね、女の子の憧れということで、
It's every girl's dream,
たくさんの方にご協力いただきました！
so many people helped out!
ありがとうございましたでござる！
Thank you very much, de-gozaru!
そして、ソロパート移り変わりまして、なりたい自分2つ目、
And now, moving on to the solo part, my second 'self I want to be',
そう、お姫様！
yes, a princess!
いや、まさか風真がお姫様なんて言うと思ってなかった皆様は
Well, for those of you who didn't think Kazama would ever say she's a princess,
びっくりかもしれませんでしたが、
you might be surprised,
心は女子。やはりお姫様に憧れるというものということで、
but my heart is a girl's. After all, one yearns to be a princess,
こちらもやらさせていただきました！
so I performed this too!
ちょっとステージ見てみましょう。ドン！
Let's take a look at the stage. Bam!
うわー、なんかお姫様のお城っぽくね？
Wow, doesn't it look like a princess's castle?
めっちゃ、凄くない？この、この、なんていうの？
Isn't it amazing? This, this, what do you call it?
こういうの、プロジェクションマッピングみたいなカッコいいあの技術で、
This cool tech like projection mapping,
あの、やってくださいました！
they used it for me!
風真には全然わかんない技術なんですけど、本当にありがとうございます！
It's tech Kazama doesn't understand at all, but thank you so much!
カボチャの馬車もあったりなんて、します！
There's even a pumpkin carriage and everything!
はい、というわけで、ちょっと一旦水を飲んでいいですか？
Yes, and so, can I have a drink of water for a moment?
ちょっと死ぬかもしれないので。
I might die otherwise.
あの、お迎えに来ちゃう王子様じゃなくて、違うものが...
Not the prince coming for me, but something else...
死ぬ死ぬ死ぬ。
I'm dying, I'm dying, I'm dying.
お待たせしました！
Sorry to keep you waiting!
あの、なんですけども、あのびっくりすることに、
Um, also, surprisingly,
もう既にXのトレンドが1位みたいです！
it seems we're already #1 trending on X!
皆様、本当にありがとうございます！
Everyone, thank you so much!
たくさんポストしてくれて本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much for all the posts!
こんなに早くていいの？ってぐらいびっくりです。
I'm so surprised, like 'is it okay to be this fast?'
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
このあとも、元気いっぱい歌って踊りますので、
I'll continue to sing and dance with lots of energy,
最後まで絶対見ていってください！
so please watch until the very end!
はい、そしてやらさせていただいた2つの曲、
Yes, and the two songs I performed,
『シンデレラ』と『白雪のプリンセスは』、
'Cinderella' and 'The Snow White Princess is...',
こちらは皆様お分かりの方も多かったと思うんですけれども、
I think many of you recognized them,
はい、『ムーン・プライド』からのこちらの3曲、
yes, these three songs starting from 'Moon Pride',
なんとショートのカウントダウンで踊ってたダンスでした！
were actually the dances I did for the Shorts countdown!
3日前が『シンデレラ』で、
Three days ago was 'Cinderella',
2日前が『白雪のプリンセスは』で、
two days ago was 'The Snow White Princess is...',
1日前が『ムーン・プライド』でした！
and one day ago was 'Moon Pride'!
ぜひね、配信終わった後に練習風景も見たいなって方は
After the stream, if you'd like to see the practice footage,
そちらのショートも...
please check out those Shorts...
見て見てください！
Look, look at this!
すごい、色々喋ること一気にガーって喋ったけど、みんなついてきてる？
Wow, I talked about so many things all at once, is everyone keeping up?
おめでとう、ありがとう！ Xのトレンド1位、ありがとう！
Congratulations, thank you! Trending #1 on X, thank you!
見てるよ！
I'm watching!
ありがとう、たくさん見てくれて、本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you, thank you so much for watching, really, thank you!
愛、届いてます！
Your love is reaching me!
はい、そして、またこの後はゲストパートに行きたいと思います。
Yes, and now, I'd like to move on to the guest part.
何やら、Xで匂わせがあったとか... もう恥ずかしいから、もう恥ずかしいなぁ、もう。
Apparently, there were some hints on X... It's so embarrassing, so embarrassing...
ちょっと直前にですね、あの、ご連絡をね、いただきまして。
Just before this, I received a message from them.
「いい？匂わせてもいいかな？いろはちゃん」ということでご連絡いただいたんですけど。
They asked me, "Is it okay? Can I drop some hints, Iroha-chan?"
そう、あの方がやって来ます。
Yes, that person is coming.
この後のお姫様パート、やはり風真いろはのお姫様といえば、
For the following princess part, when you think of Kazama Iroha's princess...
この方です！どうぞ！
It's this person! Here she is!
風を待って　鳥になって
Wait for the wind, become a bird
私より自由かな
Is it more free than me?
翼がないなら走ってく
If I don't have wings, I'll run
生きていきたいところまで
To the place I want to live in
できるよね
I can do it, right?
Going going going going
on
CLEAR / 作詞 坂本真綾 作曲 水野良樹
CLEAR / Lyrics: Maaya Sakamoto, Composition: Yoshiki Mizuno
ざわざわと街はいつも違ってる
The town is always buzzing differently
何もかも完璧とはいかないけど
Not everything goes perfectly
心の底に　歪みがあるの
There's a distortion in the bottom of my heart
どんなに落ち込んでも
No matter how depressed I get
また透明なもので満たされてゆく
I'm filled with something transparent again
これって　これって　なんていう気持ちなの
This, this, what kind of feeling is it?
熱くて　痛くて　くすぐったくて　飲み込んでしまいそう
Hot, painful, ticklish, I'm about to swallow it
風を待って　鳥になって
Wait for the wind, become a bird
私より自由かな
Is it more free than me?
翼がないなら走ってく
If I don't have wings, I'll run
生きていきたいところまで
To the place I want to live in
できるよね
I can do it, right?
Going going going going
on
他の子にあって　私にないもの
Things others have that I don't
わかってはいるけど　つい比べちゃうよ
I know it, but I end up comparing myself
答え合わせは　もうしたくない
I don't want to check the answers anymore
みんなと同じじゃなくても
Even if it's not the same as everyone else
私にできること見つけたいの
I want to find what I can do
夢って　愛って　本当はよく知らない
Dreams, love, I don't really know them
どんな色　どんな形　どこからやって来るの
What color, what shape, where do they come from?
祈って　願って　それだけじゃ叶わない
Praying, wishing, that's not enough for it to come true
自信がなくっても始めるんだ
I'll start even if I'm not confident
いつかじゃなくって今
Not "someday" but "now"
できるよね
I can do it, right?
Going going going going
on
歪みがここにあるの
There's a distortion here
私を司る水面と音が
The surface and sounds that govern me
何があっても　枯れたりしない
No matter what happens, it won't wither
諦めたつもりでも
Even if I think I've given up
また透明なもので満たされてゆく
I'm filled with something transparent again
これって　これって　なんていう気持ちなの
This, this, what kind of feeling is it?
熱くて　痛くて　くすぐったくて　飲み込んでしまいそう
Hot, painful, ticklish, I'm about to swallow it
風を待って　鳥になって
Wait for the wind, become a bird
私より自由かな
Is it more free than me?
翼がないなら走ってく
If I don't have wings, I'll run
生きていきたいところまで
To the place I want to live in
できるよね
I can do it, right?
Going going going going
on
Oh oh oh...
いつか僕らの上をすれすれに
One day, right above our heads,
通り過ぎていったあの飛行機を
that airplane that passed by,
不思議なぐらいに覚えてる
I remember it strangely well,
意味もないのになぜか
even though there's no reason why.
不甲斐なくて泣いた日の夜に
On the night of the day I cried from helplessness,
ただ強くなりたいと願ってた
I just wished to be strong.
そのために必要な勇気を
The courage I needed for that,
探し求めていた
I was searching for it.
残酷な運命が定まってるとして
Even if a cruel fate has been decided,
それがいつの日か僕の前に現れるとして
and it appears before me one day,
ただ一瞬、この一瞬、息ができるなら
If I can breathe for just a moment, this moment,
どうでもいいと思えたその心を
that heart that felt it didn't matter,
もう一度
once more.
遠くへ行け遠くへ行けと
"Go further, go further,"
僕の中で誰かが歌う
someone within me sings.
どうしようもないほど熱烈に
With an uncontrollably passionate fervor,
いつだって目を腫らした君が二度と
so that you, who always has swollen eyes,
悲しまないように笑える
can smile and never be sad again,
そんなヒーローになるための歌
this is the song to become such a hero.
さらば掲げろピースサイン
Farewell, raise your peace sign
転がっていくストーリーを
as the story rolls on.
守りたいだなんて言えるほど
Enough to say that I want to protect you,
君が弱くはないのはわかってた
I knew you weren't that weak.
それ以上に僕は弱くてさ
But I'm even weaker than that,
君が大事だったんだ
and you were important to me.
独りで生きていくんだなんてさ
Saying things like "I'll live on my own,"
口を突いて叫んだあの日から
since the day I let that out and screamed,
変わっていく僕を笑えばいい
you can just laugh at the changing me,
独りきりの強さをと
calling it the strength of being alone.
蹴飛ばして 噛み付いて
Kicking it away, biting down,
息もできなくて
unable to even breathe,
騒ぐ頭と腹の奥がぐちゃぐちゃになったって
even if my noisy head and gut get all messed up,
辛いのも 汚いのも 消えてしまうくらいに
to the point where the pain and filth vanish,
今は触っていたいだ 君の心に
right now I want to be touching your heart.
僕たちはいつか遠く離れた
One day, we'll reach out to the sun
太陽にすら手が届いて
from far, far away,
夜明け前を手に入れて笑おう
and we'll smile after obtaining the dawn.
そうやって青く燃える色に染まり
Staining ourselves in that burning blue color,
朧げな街の向こうへ
beyond the hazy town,
手を繋いで走っていけるはずだ
we should be able to run hand in hand.
君と未来を盗み描き
Stealing and sketching a future with you,
捻り出すストーリーを
this story that we squeeze out.
カサブタだらけ荒くれた日々が
The rough days full of scabs,
削り削られ擦り切れた今が
the present worn out from being scraped and shaved,
君の言葉で蘇る
they come back to life with your words,
鮮やかにも現れていく
appearing vividly before me.
蛹のままで眠る魂を
The soul sleeping inside its cocoon,
食べかけのまま捨てたあの夢を
that dream discarded half-eaten,
もう一度取り戻せ
take them back once more!
Oh oh oh...
もう一度
Once more.
遠くへ行け遠くへ行けと
"Go further, go further,"
僕の中で誰かが歌う
someone within me sings.
どうしようもないほど熱烈に
With an uncontrollably passionate fervor,
いつだって目を腫らした君が二度と
so that you, who always has swollen eyes,
悲しまないように笑える
can smile and never be sad again,
そんなヒーローになるための歌
this is the song to become such a hero.
さらば掲げろピースサイン
Farewell, raise your peace sign
転がっていくストーリーを
as the story rolls on.
君と未来を盗み描き
Stealing and sketching a future with you,
捻り出すストーリーを
this story that we squeeze out.
遥か空響いてる 祈りは奇跡に
The prayers echoing in the distant sky turn into miracles,
無謀な明日に
Into a reckless tomorrow,
...うけとめて
...Accept it
流れてく涙の粒
The flowing teardrops
迷いなく包み込む
Enveloping them without hesitation
温もりに 出会った
I encountered warmth
真っ白な雪のように
Like pure white snow
どこまでも素直な言葉
Words that are honest to the core
鉄の羽 纏った
Draped in wings of iron
僕を動かしてく
They keep me moving
傷つくたびに
Every time I get hurt
優しくなれる
I can become kinder
君のその笑顔だけ
Only that smile of yours
守り抜きたい 願いは一つ
I want to protect it to the end; I have one wish
時を越え刻まれた 悲しみの記憶
Memories of sadness carved across time
真っ直ぐに受け止める 君は光の天使
Facing them head-on, you are an angel of light
あの日胸に灯った 永遠の炎
The eternal flame that was lit in my heart that day
深い闇 解き放って
Release the deep darkness
自由の扉 開いてく
Opening the door to freedom
強く果てない未来へ
To a strong and endless future
冷たい緑の月に
In the cold, green moon
映し出す心の影
The shadow of my heart is projected
寂しげに呟いた
I whispered lonelily
君の側にいたい
I want to be by your side
真実と向き合うこと
Facing the truth
教えてくれた勇気は
The courage you taught me
僕を駆け巡って
Rushes through me
夢に目覚めてゆく
And I awaken to my dreams
触れ合う気持ち
Our mutual feelings
離れないように
So we don't drift apart
しっかりと抱きしめて
Hold them tight
確かな想い 貫いてゆく
Letting my certain feelings pierce through
銀の海に隠した 空白のページ
A blank page hidden in the silver sea
君だけが知っている 本当を僕に見せて
Show me the truth that only you know
吹き荒れる切なさに 生まれゆく誓い
A vow being born in the raging sadness
もう何も怖くはないよ
I'm not afraid of anything anymore
結んだ視線 逸らさずに
Without averting our locked gazes
大切な今 始める
Beginning this precious moment
Oh...
君が君でいられる場所を
A place where you can be yourself
幻にさらわれぬように
So it won't be snatched away by illusions
消えない過ちも 苦しみも
Unfading mistakes and suffering too
鍵を壊して ぶつけてよ
Break the lock and let it all out at me
隣にいるから
Because I'm here beside you
全てを信じて
Believe in everything
時を越え刻まれた 悲しみの記憶
Memories of sadness carved across time
真っ直ぐに受け止める 君は光の天使
Facing them head-on, you are an angel of light
あの日胸に灯った 永遠の炎
The eternal flame that was lit in my heart that day
深い闇 解き放って
Release the deep darkness
自由の扉 開いてく
Opening the door to freedom
強く果てない未来へ
To a strong and endless future
きっとここから 始まる
It surely begins from here
まるで御伽の話
Just like a fairy tale
終わり迎えた証
Proof of an ending
長過ぎる旅路から
From a journey far too long
切り出した一節
A passage carved out
まるで御伽の話 終わり迎えた証
Just like a fairy tale, proof of the end reached
長過ぎる旅路から 切り出した一節
A passage cut out from an overly long journey
それは かつて この地に
It was once upon this land
影を 落とした 悪を
The evil that cast a shadow
打ち取りし 勇者との
With the hero who defeated it
短い旅の 記憶
Memories of a short journey
勇者
The Hero
作詞・作曲：Ayase
Lyrics/Composition: Ayase
物語は 終わり
The story ends
勇者は 眠りにつく
The hero falls asleep
穏やかな 日常を
A peaceful everyday life
この地に 残して
Left behind on this land
時の流れは 無情に
The flow of time is ruthless
人を忘れさせる
Making people forget
そこに生きた 軌跡も
Even the traces of life there
錆び付いていく
Are rusting away
それでも 君の
Even so, your
言葉も 願いも 勇気も
Words, wishes, and courage
今も 確かに 私の中で
Are still certainly within me
生きている
Living on
同じ途を 選んだ
I chose the same path
それだけだった はずなのに
That should have been all, but
いつの間にか どうして
Somehow, why
頬を 伝う 涙の
The tears streaming down my cheeks
理由を もっと 知りたいんだ
I want to know the reason more
今更だって
Even if it's too late now
共に 歩んだ 旅路を 辿れば
If I trace the journey we walked together
そこに 君は 居なくても
Even if you're not there
きっと 見つけられる
I'm sure I can find it
物語は 続く
The story continues
一人の旅へと 立つ
Setting off on a journey alone
立ち寄る 街で 出会う
Meeting people in the towns I stop by
人の記憶の中に 残る君は
You who remain in people's memories
相も変わらず お人好しで
Are still a good-natured person
格好つけてばかりだね
Always trying to look cool
あちらこちらに 作った シンボルは
The symbols you made here and there
勝ち取った 平和の証
Are proofs of the peace we won
それすら 未来で いつか
Even those, in the future, someday
私が 一人に ならないように
So that I won't be alone
あの旅を 思い出せるように
So that I can remember that journey
残された 目印
Markers left behind
まるで お伽の話
Just like a fairy tale
終わり 迎えた 証
Proof of the end reached
私を 変えた 出会い
The encounter that changed me
百分の一の 旅路
A one-hundredth journey
君の勇気を いつか 風がさらって
Your courage, someday the wind will carry it away
誰の記憶から 消えてしまっても
Even if it vanishes from everyone's memory
私が 未来に 連れて行くから
I will take it with me to the future
君の手を 取った
I took your hand
あの目 全て 始まった
Everything started that day
くだらなくて 思わず
It was so trivial that I couldn't help
ふっと 笑ってしまうような
But chuckle for a moment
ありふれた 時間が 今も眩しい
Those common times are still dazzling
知りたいんだ 今更だって
I want to know, even if it's too late now
振り返ると そこには いつでも
When I look back, you are always there
優しく 微笑みかける
Smiling gently at me
君がいるから
Because you are here
新たな 旅の 始まりは
The start of a new journey
新たな旅の始まりは 君が守り抜いたこの地に 芽吹いた命と共に
The start of a new journey, in this land you protected, together with the life that sprouted
君が 守り抜いた この地に
In this land you protected to the end
芽吹いた 命と共に
Together with the life that sprouted
はい！というわけで、皆様たくさん続けて、あの、見ていただきました！
Alright! So, everyone, you've watched a lot in a row!
ゲストパート1曲目、えっと、プリンセスパートの
The first guest song, during the Princess Part
あづきちと一緒に『Clear』！
with Azuki-chi, was 'Clear'!
そして、今回またステージ変わりまして、こちら、
And now the stage has changed again.
次の『なりたい自分』、ヒーローということで、ヒーローテーマでやらせていただきました！
For the next 'self I want to be,' it's a Hero, so I performed with a Hero theme!
『ピースサイン』をかなた先輩と、そして『ADAMAS』ブレイザーですね、
I performed 'Peace Sign' with Kanata-senpai, and 'ADAMAS' - the blazer version -
かなた先輩とあづきちと3人でやらせていただきました！
as a trio with Kanata-senpai and Azuki-chi!
いかがだったでしょうか！？
How was it?!
めっちゃかっこよかった！
It was so cool!
かっこよかった、ヒーロー！ そうだよ、風真いろはかっこいいんだよってことを
Cool Hero! Yes, I'm glad I could show everyone
みんなに知ってもらえて嬉しいでござる！ ありがとうございます！
that Iroha Kazama is cool! Thank you so much!
はい。実はですね、あの、今回皆様お気づきかと思うんですけども、
Yes. Actually, as you might have noticed,
3Dのあの、一番最初、えっと、1周年の時ぶりですね、
this is the first time since my 1st anniversary 3D live
あの、お呼びしたあづきちと、ホロックス以外にお呼びしたあづきちと、
that I've invited guests other than holoX members.
あとかなた先輩に今回はそれぞれまた1曲ずつお願いして、で、最後は3人でやりたいなということで、お願いさせていただきました！
I invited Azuki-chi and Kanata-senpai to perform one song each, and finally, I asked them to do a song as a trio!
本当にありがとうございました、先輩方！
Thank you so much, senpais!
本当にありがとうございました！ めちゃくちゃ楽しかったです！
Truly, thank you! It was so much fun!
はい。やっぱりですね、『なりたい自分』、今回そしてヒーローで、
Yes. After all, 'the self I want to be,' this time as a Hero,
あの、コラボパートから始まったんですけども、やっぱり、道を歩いて行こうということで、
which started from the collab part, I wanted to walk the path,
憧れるヒーロー、やはり『勇者』が一番合いますね！
so the hero I admire, 'The Hero' (Yuusha), fits perfectly!
めちゃくちゃ難しかったんですけど、死ぬほど練習して、あの、歌えるようになりました！
It was incredibly difficult, but I practiced like crazy to be able to sing it!
息継ぎとかね、めっちゃ大変だったんですけど、細かく、こうやってボイトレの先生に
The breathing was so hard, but my vocal coach
教えていただいたりとかして、歌えるようになった『勇者』、それをダンス付きで頑張らせていただきました！
helped me with the details, and I worked hard to perform 'The Hero' with dancing!
みんながかっこよかったって...
Everyone saying I was cool...
...言ってくれるの嬉しすぎて今もう半分涙ちょちょぎれてるんですけど
...makes me so happy, I'm almost in tears.
本当にありがとうございます
Thank you so much.
振りすごかった、
The choreography was amazing,
かっこよかった、
it was so cool,
歌もすごかった！ありがとうございます！
and the singing was great too! Thank you!
はい、ちょっとね、まだまだ皆殿と一緒に喜びを噛み締めていきたいところなんですけども、
Well, I'd like to keep savoring this joy
with everyone,
やっぱみんなも待っているかなと思って、
but I'm sure everyone is waiting,
そろそろ告知しないといけないかなと思って。
so I think it's about time
I made the announcements.
聞きたいよね？
You want to hear them, right?
皆殿、聞きたいよね？
Everyone wants to hear them, right?
というわけで、少し休憩かつ告知タイムをさせて頂ければと思いますので、
So, I'll take a little break and do
the announcement time.
お付き合いください。
Please stick with me.
それではまず一つ目の告知、
Now, for the first announcement!
それでは行きます、
Here we go!
ドドン！
Ta-da!
はい、今年も出ます、
Yes, it's back this year!
風真いろは誕生日記念グッズ2024の販売決定しましたー！イエーイ！
The Kazama Iroha Birthday Commemorative Goods
2024! Yay!
めちゃくちゃ可愛いイラストですね！
The illustration is so cute!
今回は「まじかる☆ござる」なんとグッズになりますので、
This time, "Magical Gozaru"
is featured on the goods.
皆殿、最後までラインナップ見てってくださいね！
Everyone, please check out the lineup
until the end.
それでは詳細を見ていきましょう。
Now, let's look at the details.
まずは、こちら！
First is this!
はい、まじかる☆ござるTシャツ！
Yes, the Magical Gozaru T-shirt!
なんと、みんな大好き「ござるさん」を胸元にあしらった素敵なTシャツでございます。
It's a wonderful T-shirt featuring everyone's
favorite "Gozaru-san" on the chest.
こちら、あの、描かせていただきました。
I drew this one myself.
そして背中には、えっと、コンセプトのイラストになっている、
And on the back is the concept illustration.
こちら、まじかる☆ござるのイラストを豆岡田先生にお願いいたしました。ありがとうございます！
I asked Mame-Oda-sensei for this
Magical Gozaru illustration. Thank you!
本当にめちゃくちゃ可愛い、ありがとうございます！
It's really, really cute! Thank you!
ぜひ皆殿に着てもらえたら嬉しいなと思っております。
I'd be happy if everyone wore it.
そして、今後ね、あの風真いろはの生誕祭とかやる時の
And from now on, for any
Kazama Iroha birthday events,
スタッフさんはね、みんなこれ着用が義務付けられてますので、
it's mandatory for all the staff to wear this,
見る側の皆殿もこれ着用義務なんで、よろしくお願いします。
and for everyone watching, it's also
mandatory. Thank you.
ぜひ着てくださいね！よろしくお願いします！
Please everyone, wear it! Thank you!
はい、返事ももらえました！
Okay, I got some replies!
じゃあ、それでは次、こちら！
Now for the next one, this!
はい、まじかる☆ござるフォンタブ！
Yes, the Magical Gozaru Phone Tab!
Xで話した時に、みんな「知らなかった」って言われたのがすごく多くて、
When I talked about this on X, many people
said they didn't know what it was.
「へ、意外」と思ったんですけど、
I was like, "Really?" but here it is!
はい、こちらフォンタブでございます。
This is the phone tab.
クリアケースに挟んで、あの、充電ケーブル挿すところから出して、
You put it in a clear case, thread the
strap through the charging port,
で、ストラップをつけて、首から下げる、
and hang it from your neck.
皆殿のスマホをお守りします、「安全第一」のフォンタブとなっております。
It's a "Safety First" phone tab that
protects everyone's phones.
ぜひね、皆殿、イベントとかね、スマホパッと出せた方が便利だと思うので、
It'll be handy at events where you need
to take out your phone quickly.
ぜひ使ってもらえたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you used it.
はい、そして次、めちゃ喜ぶよ、みんな、こちら！
Okay, and next is something everyone
will love! This!
はい、「ぽこべぇになりきりいろは」ぬいぐるみー！
Yes, the "Poko-be-becoming-Iroha" Plushie!
というわけで、いやー、言ってたね、みんな。
Well, everyone was saying they wanted
something like this.
ぽこべぇの、ね、なんか色々、なったファンアートとか見ていて思いついたんですけど、
I got the idea from fan art of Poko-be
becoming different things.
これは、ぽこべぇがい・いろはになっているのか、いろはがぽこべぇになっているのか、正直よく分かりません。
I'm not sure if it's Poko-be becoming
Iroha or Iroha becoming Poko-be.
はい、ではなく、今回、風真いろはがぽこべぇになりきってコスプレした特別なぬいぐるみになっております。
Actually, it's a special plushie of
Kazama Iroha cosplaying as Poko-be.
はい、このぽこべぇのもふもふ感と、ござるの、この何とも言えない「ホエ〜？」とした顔を一緒にお楽しみください。
Please enjoy this Poko-be fluffiness and
"Gozaru's" indescribable expression.
はい、なんと、カラビナ付いてますので、ぜひ皆殿もね、連れて歩いてもらえると嬉しいです。
It even has a carabiner, so I'd be happy
if you carried it around with you.
こちらは、デザイン、さめあんこ先生にお願いさせて頂きました。
For the design, I asked Sameanko-sensei.
ぜひ、皆殿、たくさんゲットしてね！
Everyone, please get a lot of them!
はい、そして次が、こちら！
Okay, and the next one is this!
はい、「ござるさんつきバケットハット」ってことで。
Yes, the Bucket Hat with Gozaru-san!
いやー、ちょっとね、やっぱ「ブランド化」っていうのを目指していこうと思って。
Well, I'm trying to aim for a "branded"
feel.
やっぱ、いろんな「なりたい自分」があるけど、やっぱみんながさ、「ブランド化」を望んでくれたらなれるんじゃないかと思って、
I have many "wanted selves," but if everyone
wants a brand, maybe we can do it!
今回作らせていただきました。
So I decided to make it this time.
はい、こちらですね、Tシャツとセットで着ていただくと、なんと「全身ござるさんコーデ」ができちゃうという。
If you wear it with the T-shirt, you'll have
a full "Gozaru-san" coordinate!
代物になっておりますので、これを機に、ぜひ皆殿ゲットしてくださいね！
It's a great item, so please take this
chance to get it.
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you!
はい、そして次、こちらが、えっと...
And the next one is...
一応、紹介しますか。じゃあ、こちらお願いします。
I'll introduce it just in case.
Here it is.
えーっと、「まじかる☆ござるの元気の出る魔法」、シチュエーションボイスとなっております。
It's a situation voice pack called
"Magical Gozaru's Magic to Make You Feel Better."
まあ、元気のない方におすすめで、今回も頑張ってボイスなど撮らせて頂いておりますが、
Recommended for those feeling low.
I did my best recording it.
えー、聞く聞かないは皆様のご自由でございますので、
Whether you listen to it or not
is up to you.
あの、そっと聴いていただけると嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします。
Please listen to it quietly. Thank you.
はい、じゃあ、次行こうか。はい、次次次、次次次！
Okay, let's move on! Next, next, next!
はい、フルセットはこちら、こんな感じになってます！
Here is the full set! It looks like this!
全部可愛いでしょー！
Everything is so cute, right?
そして、今回もあります。
And there's more this time too.
えっと、フルセット、今回もあります、購入特典がこちら！
The purchase bonus for the full set is this!
はい、数量限定直筆サインあります！
Yes, a handwritten signature in
limited quantities!
でも、今回はめちゃ多めにしたから許して！
But I made a lot more this time,
so please forgive me!
本当に多めにしたの！
I really made a lot!
この後、22時カートオープンなので、
Cart opens at 10 PM tonight.
数量限定なんですけど、直筆サインは本当にめちゃ頑張って増やしたんで、許してください。
They are limited, but I worked really hard
to increase the number of signed ones.
お願いします。
Please.
そして、数量限定関係なく、フルセットをご購入頂いた方には、
And regardless of the limited quantity,
if you buy the full set,
ASMRのボイスが付いてくるんだって。
you'll get an ASMR voice pack!
ASMRって何だっけ？
ASMR... what was that again?
あ、記憶が遠くなっていくな。
Oh, my memory is fading.
でも、確か一緒に誕生日を過ごすシチュエーションを撮った気がする。
But I think I recorded a situation about
spending a birthday together.
あ、今日「緊張」という言葉を捨ててきたんでね、これ以上は...
Oh, I discarded the word "nervous" today,
so no more of that.
...ということでぜひ興味のある方はフルセットを購入して聴いてみてください。
...So if you're interested, please buy the full set and listen to it.
はい。そして...
Yes. And...
...変わらずこの後ですね、ライブが長引く可能性ありますが...
...as always, after this, there's a possibility the live might run long, but...
カートオープンは22時からなので皆様ちょっとライブ見ながら、
the merch cart opens at 22:00, so while watching the live,
あの、戦ってもらえると嬉しいです。すみません、よろしくお願いします。
I'd be happy if you could fight for it. Sorry, and thank you.
そして、次の告知です。
And here's the next announcement.
はい。
Yes.
この後22時15分からメンバーシップ限定でアンコールライブを開催いたします。
After this, from 22:15, we will hold an encore live exclusively for members.
今までみんなの前でやったことなかったぼっちなんちゃらとか
I'll be doing 'Bocchi-something' and
ぼっちなんちゃらとかぼっちなんちゃらを、なんと今回ですね、アンコールライブでやらせていただきますので、
'Bocchi-whatever' which I've never done in public, in the encore live,
ぜひ、まだまだござるの歌やダンスが聴きたい見たいぞって方はねメンバーシップ入ってみてもらえると嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします。
so if you want to see more of my singing and dancing, please consider joining the membership. Thank you.
そして、皆様、大切な告知があともう1つあるんですけど。
And everyone, there's one more important announcement.
風を仰ぎしで陽な、そして交わるござる、来るまでに1/3、2/3と刻んでまいりました。
Leading up to this point, I've checked off 1/3 and 2/3 of my announcements.
それでは、3/3を告知させていただきます。それがこちら、ドドン！
Now, let me make the 3/3 announcement. Here it is! Ta-da!
はい！この後24時からリリース、えーと風真いろは4曲目のオリジナル曲「Dreamy Sky」をリリースさせていただくことになりました！
Yes! Starting from midnight today, I'll be releasing my 4th original song, 'Dreamy Sky'!
やったー！
Yay!
そして22時5分からライブが終わった後、5分10分かちょっとあの、ライブの終了時間にもよるんですけど、プレミア公開が、えー待機しておりますので、
And after the live ends, around 22:05 or so depending on the time, the premiere will be waiting,
ぜひ皆様ね、この後プレミア公開見に行ってください。
so please go watch the premiere afterwards.
素敵な曲はpiccoさんが作ってくださいました。キラキラふわふわの可愛い曲です。よろしくお願いします。
This wonderful song was created by picco-san. It's a sparkling, fluffy, and cute song. Thank you.
はい。
Yes.
そしてこちらなんですけども、この後のパートで、えーダンスをですね、初披露させていただきまして、歌も初披露させていただきまして、
And for this song, in the next part, I'll be performing the dance and the song for the first time,
えっと、なんて言ったらいいんだろ、MVの後ろでちょっとね、流しちゃったりなんかするんですけども、
and, how should I put it, I'll be showing a bit of it in the background of the MV, but...
あのダンスをですね、今日実は近くに、あのいつもダンスレッスンお世話になってる先生が来てくださってるんですけど、なんと、
about that dance, the teacher who always helps me with my dance lessons is actually here today, and...
結構共作で、共同制作でですね、一生懸命作らせていただいた振り付けなので、
it's a choreography that we worked very hard on together as a collaboration,
ぜひ、いろんな方に踊っていただけると嬉しいなと思っておりますので、よろしくお願いします。ダンスもよかったら注目して見てください。
so I'd be happy if many people danced to it. Thank you. Please pay attention to the dance as well.
最後まで応援よろしくお願いします。
Please support me until the end.
その前に、お水を飲んできてよろしいでしょうか。
Before that, may I go drink some water?
お水飲ませてください、本当に。お水、お水...
Please let me drink some water, really. Water, water...
お水飲まないと死んじゃうよ。
I'll die if I don't drink water.
ああ、それにしてもお水が、お水が、お水が、お水が。ちょっと待って、待ってねみんな、ちょっといっぱい飲まないと死ぬかもしれない。
Ah, anyway, water, water, water... wait a second, everyone, I might die if I don't drink a lot.
はい。
Okay.
はい、そうしますと皆様、ちょっと一応ね、スタッフさんにもう一度言っとけって言われたんで、ほぼ確定で22時ちょっと押しちゃいそうなので、申し訳ないです本当に。
Alright then, everyone, the staff told me to mention it again, but it's almost certain that we'll run past 22:00 a bit, so I'm really sorry.
あの、カート皆様、ちょっと準備万端にしといてください。よろしくお願いします。グッズのカート準備万端にしといてください。よろしくお願いします。
Everyone, please have your carts ready. Thank you. Please have your merch carts ready. Thank you.
はい。それではお待たせいたしました。
Yes. Then, thank you for waiting.
えー、ここで新しいオリ曲「Dreamy Sky」を初披露させていただきます。
Now, I'll be performing my new original song, 'Dreamy Sky,' for the first time.
それでは聴いてください。風真いろは4曲目オリジナルソング、「Dreamy Sky」。
Please listen. Kazama Iroha's 4th original song, 'Dreamy Sky'.
Let's Go! ときめいた青空で
Let's Go! In the heart-pounding blue sky
もっと風に乗りきらめくの
Ride the wind and sparkle more
Dreaming
今より可愛くなりたい
I want to be cuter than I am now
Cuteな想い ほら何度でもバッキュンだ！
These cute feelings, look, I'll shoot them through your heart again and again!
まぶたに映るほうき星
A shooting star reflected on my eyelids
夜空の中 飛びこんだ Shiny Girl
A Shiny Girl who jumped into the night sky
手が届きそうなほど
So close that I could almost reach
近づく三日月 合図して
The crescent moon approaches, give the signal
街の明かりも数えたら
If I count the city lights too
眠りにつく枕元 Secret Girl
By the bedside as I fall asleep, Secret Girl
まだ見つからない
I haven't found it yet
夢探しに行こう
Let's go look for a dream
雨の日でも 晴れの日でも
Whether it's a rainy day or a sunny day
真っ直ぐに咲いてる 花のように
Like a flower blooming straight and true
いつだってきっと どこだってそっと
Always, surely, anywhere, softly
輝く魔法
The magic that shines
Let's Go! ときめいた青空で
Let's Go! In the heart-pounding blue sky
もっと風に乗りきらめくの
Ride the wind and sparkle more
Dreaming
今より可愛くなりたい
I want to be cuter than I am now
Cuteな想い ほら何度でもバッキュンだ！
These cute feelings, look, I'll shoot them through your heart again and again!
華やかドレス 身にまとい
Wrapped in a glamorous dress
誰かを待つ憧れの Princess Girl
Waiting for someone, the long-awaited Princess Girl
あーなりたい理想と比べてばっか
Ah, always comparing myself to my ideal
道に迷って一人悩んで
Losing my way, worrying all by myself
くじけそうになっても大丈夫
Even if I'm about to give up, it's okay
君と出会って笑顔になって
Meeting you and finding my smile
輝く魔法
The magic of shining
Let's Go!
ありふれた日常も
Even the most ordinary days
もっと風吹いて動き出す
Start moving with more wind
Jumping 飛び立つ希望を探して
Jumping, looking for hope to take flight
弾ける想いほら何度でもバッキュンだ！
My popping feelings, look, "Bang!" again and again!
助けられるだけじゃ嫌
I don't want to just be saved
わたしも守りたい
I want to protect too
そうずっと思い描いた
Yes, the days I've always imagined
日々を繋いで重なるいろは
Connecting those days, the overlapping colors
やっと気づいた本当の願い
Finally realized my true wish
なんてちょっぴり大袈裟だけど
It's a bit of an exaggeration, but
どうかこの時間がいつまでも
Please let this time last forever
続きますように君といま
So that it continues, with you right now
Let's Go! ときめいた青空で
Let's Go! In the sparkling blue sky
もっと風に乗り煌めくの
Riding the wind more and sparkling
Dreaming 今より可愛くなりたい
Dreaming, I want to be cuter than I am now
ギュッとな想いほら何度でもバッキュンだ！
My tight feelings, look, "Bang!" again and again!
皆様！このライブも最後の曲になりました！
Everyone! This live concert has come to the final song!
今回は3回目の誕生日なので、「愛言葉Ⅳ」を歌って終わりにします。
Since this is my third birthday, I'll end by singing "Ai Kotoba IV."
今日は本当に来てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for coming today!
想いの冒険を
The adventure of my feelings
忘れずに全部言えるかな
Can I say it all without forgetting?
君から聞きたいよ
I want to hear it from you
何回目の僕に出会った？
How many versions of me have you met?
僕は変わりました
I have changed
新しい君に出会うために
In order to meet the new you
久しぶりだねって
Saying "It's been a long time"
言えたならここで泣こっか
If I could say that, let's cry here
好きとかって嫌いとかって
Saying I like you or I hate you
何度だって愛を歌う君が
Singing about love again and again, you
恋しくって嘘じゃない本当だよ
I miss you, it's not a lie, it's the truth
また出会おう
Let's meet again
僕ら"Ⅱ"を贈って"Ⅰ"に戻って
We send "II" and return to "I"
何回だって間違ってきたよ
We've made mistakes again and again
消えない後悔と冷めない愛情が
The lingering regrets and the never-cooling affection
恋を再起動する
Reboot our love
ほら"Ⅰ"を贈ってまた"Ⅱ"に戻って
Look, we send "I" and return to "II" again
"Ⅲ"になって愛を咲いていこう
"III" is reached, let's make our love bloom
言いたい感情は伝えたい正解は
The feelings I want to express, the answer I want to convey
たったひとつだけ
Is just one thing
ありがとう
Thank you
想いの冒険は
The adventure of my feelings
これからもちゃんと続いていく
Will continue properly from now on too
3と9に乗って
Riding on 3 and 9
言葉と飛び越えちゃって
Leaping over words
君も変わりました
You have changed too
新しい誰かに会うために
In order to meet someone new
大人になりました
We have become adults
それだけでいいと思えた
I felt that's enough
好きとかって嫌いとかって
Saying I like you or I hate you
何度だって愛を歌う君が
Singing about love again and again, you
恋しくって嘘じゃない本当だよ
I miss you, it's not a lie, it's the truth
また出会おう
Let's meet again
"恋"をしてバカ
Making a "love" of myself, fool
"愛"にしてバカ
Turning it into "love", fool
バカでいいこの先もずっとこのまま
It's okay to be a fool, like this from now on too
バカ
Fool
僕らに"11"を贈って
Give us an "11"
"1"に戻って
And go back to "1"
何回だって 間違ってきたよ
No matter how many times, we've made mistakes
消えない後悔と 冷めない愛情が
Unfading regrets and uncooling affection
恋を再起動する
Will restart our love
ほら "1"を贈って
Look, give a "1"
また "11"に戻って
And go back to "11" again
"111"になって
Become "111"
愛を繋いでいこう
Let's keep connecting our love
言いたい感情は
The feelings I want to say,
伝えたい正解は
The right answer I want to convey,
たったひとつだけ
There is only one:
ありがとう
Thank you
メーデー 僕と判っても もう抱き締めなくていいんだよ
Mayday, even if you know it's me, you don't have to hold me anymore
終わんない愛を抱いてたくないの もっとちゃんと不安にしてよ
I don't want to hold an endless love, make me properly anxious
妄想感傷代償連盟 愛を抱いて理想を掲んだ
Delusion Sentiment Compensation Federation, I held love and ideals
行き場のある愛のメロディーを 今
A melody of love that has a place to go, now
これまでにありがとう
Thank you for everything until now
いつまでも君と
Forever with you
「こんな歌あったね」って
Saying, "There was a song like this,"
出会いを数えられるように
So that we can count our encounters
今日は最後まで誕生日ライブ見てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you for watching my birthday live until the end today!
本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
またねー！
See you later!
風真いろは生誕ライブ Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2024
Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2024